<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erykor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://erykor.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Erykor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 20:52:17 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erykor.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culitivating PhD Skills Without One</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/culitivating-phd-skills-without-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 20:52:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/culitivating-phd-skills-without-one/</guid>
      <description>Credit: Created by GPT-4, and prompted by me.
As a software engineer, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by the deep and specialized knowledge that comes with a PhD. But does one really need to dive into years of academic research to harness the power of those covted skils? The answer, I&amp;rsquo;ve found, is a resound &amp;ldquo;no.&amp;rdquo; Her&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ve been cultivating PhD-level skills wihtout having one, focusing on my journey in the tech industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Travel a Good Way to Cure Boredom</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/is-travel-a-good-way-to-cure-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 21:01:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/is-travel-a-good-way-to-cure-boredom/</guid>
      <description>We all find boredom some time. And in such situation, travel seems to be the solution for many people, including myself. I recently had a travel in Japan for a week to escape from boredom, and since then I begin to doubt the meaning of travel and if it&amp;rsquo;s a cure for boredom.
Boredom is more about the inner mind, not about the outside experience. Yes, travel does provide some new experience, and the tireness that makes you want to return home, but such cure is temporary, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cure the root cause of boredom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/over-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 11:25:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/over-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Do we need to pursue 100% efficiency? I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking the question for a while and my answer is, NO.
100% efficiency makes us feel the need to utilize every resource we have, even when it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary, and this can indeed lead to wasted efforts, stress, reduced productivity, and suppressed creativity.
What&amp;rsquo;s the reason behind the 100%-efficiency mindset?
 Fear of Waste: We&amp;rsquo;re conditioned by education that to waste is bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deal With Frustration Productively</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/deal-with-frustration-productively/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 21:11:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/deal-with-frustration-productively/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m upset because I just found that my long-term barber upgraded my service without notifying me and charged me more money for a while. Such situations do happen in life, yet my way to deal with them is immature and unproductive.
When I first notified the unexpected price increase, I was confused and immediately angry and resentful such than I want to immediately stop using their service. Then I was overwhelmed with accusatory emotion, made a poor argument, and got a reply from my barger that he actually gave me discount for the upgraded service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do What AI Cannot Do</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/do-what-ai-cannot-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 09:04:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/do-what-ai-cannot-do/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used GPT4 a while and is surprised by it in many times. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I should focus more on what AI cannot do even 10 years later, which will be the real assets in the future. I had some ideas of what they are, and I confirmed my conclusions after some chatting with GPT4.
Link: https://chat.openai.com/share/052e3cc6-3773-48dd-9922-15dff80c28e6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain Focus Amid Failure</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/maintain-focus-amid-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 08:01:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/maintain-focus-amid-failure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I feel demotivated to do a task with high chance of failure and I want to improve that. After chatting with GPT4, I&amp;rsquo;ve got some nice advice.
The key is to reframe our perspectives: Instead of viewing the task as a likely failure, consider it as a learning opportunity. We&amp;rsquo;ll gain knowledge, skills, and experiences that will be beneficial in our future endeavors, regardless of the outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear Of Success</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/fear-of-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 20:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/fear-of-success/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t realize success is unconsciously perceived as a threat by myself until recently.
The concept of fearing success may seem counterintuitive. After all, isn&amp;rsquo;t success what we all strive for? However, &amp;lsquo;achievemephobia&amp;rsquo;, or the fear of success, is a genuine psychological condition that prevents many individuals from reaching their full potential. Those afflicted may subconsciously sabotage their own efforts, creating self-imposed barriers to their success. This fear is often rooted in past experiences, learned behaviors, and societal conditioning, making it a complex issue to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Feel A Problem Is Hard</title>
      <link>https://erykor.github.io/posts/why-we-feel-a-problem-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 12:40:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erykor.github.io/posts/why-we-feel-a-problem-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>When we perceive a problem as difficult, this hardness can be attributed to various factors. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to demystify the concept and develop a more precise and shared understanding of it. Here are some factors that contribute to the difficulty of a problem:
 Hidden and implicit information: Critical information required for solving the problem may be missing, and you need to identify what that information is. This often requires adopting a different perspective from your normal view.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
